let's look at the solution for the part
two of our one cycle quiz where we are
looking at reservation stations and
trying to figure out what's happening to
them to figure out what happens to
reservation stations we need to figure
out whether there is something that
issues so does this instruction issue
what happens to the instruction that is
broadcasting its result and is there any
result capturing in the remaining
reservation stations we can do this in
any order but we have to be careful if
multiple updates are needed to the same
field so let's try to do it just you
know let's receive what issuing is going
to do well when we are issuing we are
going to look for a free reservation
station there is one so this reservation
station becomes occupied this is an add
instruction so we put that here and it
adds f0 and f1 we consult the right here
to check what are we going to do both of
these are pointing at reservation
stations so first operand is whatever
ra0 produces and our second operand is
whatever rs1 produces but that's not the
end we also need to consider what
happens when a result is broadcast what
happens then is that this instruction
freeze its reservation station so this
one is not going to be occupied anymore
at the end of this cycle I put an X here
but what you should have done is not
select this one is still busy this one
of course remains busy the result that
is broadcast here is captured by anybody
waiting for RS 0 so this here becomes
4.4 thus this is a change it you needed
to make this one here stays the same
actually this reservation station is
free so it doesn't matter what's here
but it stays the same and then this one
that we just put in a reservation
station needs to capture the 4.4
otherwise things that are not going to
go well so this needs to happen in the
same cycle the processor won't work well
if we left it
r is 0 because r0 is never going to
broadcast anything this instruction is
still waiting for RS one and that's fine
artist one hasn't executed yet so this
is all that happens to reservation
stations as a result of things that
happen in this cycle